

PERSONAL

- Name Rotaru Florin
- **Address** street Ciobanasi nr.43, Ploiestori, Blejoi, Prahova 107070 Ploiesti
- Phone number +40735143019
- Email florin_rot@yahoo.com

INTERESTS

- BIM and Digital Technology
- Programming language-Python
- Linux and Unix operating system

ROTARU FLORIN

BIM/Digital Engineering specialist and professionally qualified Mechanical Engineer with immense 6+year experience in Revit, Plant3D, Advance Steel and Mechanical modeling, Scan to BIM, Coordination and Design optimization,

Multiple Projects Co-ordination including High-Rise, Commercial Buildings and Process Plant Layout and Piping Design.

I have achieved high productivity and time efficiency in BIM projects simultaneously using Revit, Autocad Plant3D and Navisworks for clash detection.

Being a BIM practitioner and having a solid background in BIM/VDC with sound knowledge in Revit, Autocad Plant3D and Navisworks,

I have had opportunities to render my services to take the project from a nascent stage to develop fully

to construction set of documentation through various necessary stages with complete Co-ordination and management.



EDUCATION AND QUALIFICATIONS

Oct 2007 - Jul 2010 Master's degree.

PETROLEUM-GAS UNIVERSITY OF PLOIEŞTI, Ploiesti

Bachelor's degree. Oct 2001 - Jul 2007

PETROLEUM-GAS UNIVERSITY OF PLOIEŞTI, Ploiesti

Sep 1998 - Jul 2001 High-school

Energy Technological High School "Elie Radu", Ploiesti



WORK EXPERIENCE

Nov 2017 - Present

BIM Specialist

AECOM, Bucharest

- Responsible for managing CAD hardware and software systems for the design teams;
- Identify opportunities and recommendations for increasing workflow efficiencies;
- Recommend best practices for solutions to meet customer business
- Configuration, implementation, maintenance of computer aided engineering applications in the field of computer aided design

Mar 2017 - Nov 2017 BIM COORDINATOR / Mechanical Enginner

Tebodin Consultants & Engineers SRL, Bucharest

- Manage database settings for PLANT3D
- Manage database settings for Revit
- Assigned to Tebodin Netherland Elsloo Office
- Responsible for align with others office from Tebodin Europe

Feb 2013 - Mar 2017

Mechanical Enginner

Tebodin Consultants & Engineers SRL, Ploiesti

- Manage database settings for PLANT3D, Navisworks and Revit
- Manage general arrangement, isometrics and 3D Models
- Owner for four buildings
- Detailed 3D modelling of equipment, pipe routings according to P&ID's, supports using Plant 3D, piping classes
- Assigned to Tebodin Ukraine CFI Lviv Office for tender phase and I was involved for basic piping studies, 3D routing using Revit MEP according to

P&IDs, and modelling equipment, general arrangement of piping and equipment, MTO for the utility systems of a car factory (automotive industry), piping input for CAPEX

- 3D piping routing using Cadworx, Isometrics
- Modeling and documentation for Detail design for Burcioaia & Madulari
- Site survey for Petrom project
- Detail design for Petrom project
- Conceptual / Feed phase for Petrom project
- Data sheet (static and dynamic equipment)
- **Drawings for Equipment**
- Specifications for Equipment
- Installation Manual
- Calculation Notes for vessel pressure and tank

Nov 2009 - Feb 2013 Mechanical Engineer

SC Uzuc Proiect SRL Ploiesti, Ploiesti

• Preparation of final documentation using AutoCAD software (approval drawings and execution details of pressure vessels and mechanical constructions: constructive dimensions, measurement reports, welding joints and their appropriate nondestructive examination, in accordance with applicable normative and/or client's requirements)ASME Code Sect VIII, EN 13445, Ped 5500

Aug 2007 - Nov 2009

Mechanical Enginner

SC IPIP S.A., Ploiesti

• Calculation of existing equipment in the refinery project supervision verifier. Preparing detail drawings of equipment in the plant refinery for Lukoil and Petrobrazi

Aug 1998 - Jul 2007

Electrician

SC Spoting S.A, Ploiesti

- Installation for protection against accidental touch voltages
- Installation of lightning protection of buildings against the effects
- Mounting apparatus and elements of measurement and control equipment and technological pipelines
- Plants signal for transmitting information, and installation of
- Attendants electricians used as heating systems (switches, pots and
- Containers for technological equipment)



SKILLS

Revit	****
Autocad Plant3D	****
Autocad	****
Navisworks	****
Inventor	****
Solidworks	****
Advance Steel	****
Civil3D	****
SolidEdge	****
Python	****
Dynamo	$\star\star\star\star\star$